

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER · APPLICATION DEVELOPER

458 NE Delaware Ave, Apt 416, Ankeny, IA 50021

□ (+1) 515-782-2960 | weer.referee@hotmail.com | unstoppablemango

## **Summary**

Current Application Developer at Kum & Go in Des Moines. 4 years experience specializing in full stack development with a focus on backend systems and architecture. Passion programmer, hobby sysadmin, and Linux enthusiast. Interested in complex problemsolving and procuring the right tools for the job.

### Skills\_\_\_\_

**DevOps** Azure, Azure DevOps, Docker, Jenkins

**Back-end** ASP.NET Core, MVC, gRPC **Front-end** Angular, Blazor, HTML5, SASS

**Programming** C#, Typescript, SQL, Node.js, Java, C++/C

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

Kum & Go Des Moines, IA

APPLICATION DEVELOPER Jan. 2018 - Present

• Developed a food ordering management solution for store associates to track and prioritize orders submitted via mobile and web applications.

- Built fully automated CI/CD pipelines on Azure Pipelines for applications ranging from console batch applications to containerized Docker web services.
- Designed and developed the service architecture for a cloud based enterprise food menu management solution in Azure.
- Upgraded numerous legacy applications to run more efficiently and effectively on modern technologies such as .NET Core.
- Worked with 3rd party vendors to design, develop, and deploy a cloud based mobile food ordering platform.

#### **Principal Financial Group**

Des Moines, IA

APPLICATION DEVELOPER INTERN

Jun. 2017 - Aug. 2017

- Implemented decision making and process improvements to applications in the underwriting process pipeline.
- Refactored and re-structured legacy insurance policy applications to improve overall system performance.
- Introduced new integration testing practices for Java REST APIs using mock REST clients and re-usable Docker test environments.
- Deployed automated CI/CD pipelines for Java Spring web services on WebSphere using Jenkins.

Kum & Go West Des Moines, IA

APPLICATION DEVELOPER INTERN

Jun. 2016 - May 2017, Sep. 2017 - Dec. 2017

- Implemented a customer data management tool for the Customer Relations team built on AngularJS and backed by an ASP.NET REST API.
- Automated processes for updating and managing customer rewards program information.
- Responded to requests for IT assistance from the Customer Relations team.

#### **University of Wisconsin Platteville**

Platteville, WI Sep. 2015 - May 2016

• Initiated one-on-one review sessions with students.

- Guided class activities and assignments.
- Managed a computer lab to assist with student education.

#### **Education**

PEER TUTOR

#### **University of Wisconsin Platteville**

Platteville, Wisconsin

Sep. 2013 - Dec. 2017

• Dean's Honours List

**B.S. IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING**